Mariano Riva Palacio Collection:
University of Texas at Austin
- Enero-Junio 1850
  - 4375 Mata, José Manuel de. San Felipe, June 28, 1850. LS., 1 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Request that Padre Juan Vargas be sent to aid the Padre Vicario.
  - 4376 Terreros, Manuel. Mexico, June 28, 1850. ALS., 1 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Illness of Pérez Tejada; return to duty in Cuautitlán; progress of cholera; visit with daughter of Juan Goribar; remedies for cholera; Calle de Cadena.
  - 4377 Villar, José del. San Ángel, June 28, 1850. ALS., 2 l. 22 × 29 cm.
    Progress of epidemic; remedies used; Xochimilco; illness of Cura López and Luis Valencia; flood in Churubusco; execution of Gorvalán; Padres del Carmen; shortage of priests; slow collection of tax in Coyoacán; troubles caused by articles in El Universal and Huracán; Aguirre.
  - 4378 Pérez Tejada, Joaquín. Hacienda de la Teja, June 28, 1850. LS., 2 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Visit to Municipalidad de Monte Bajo; illness with cholera; plan to move to Cuautitlán; cholera in Tlalnepantla, Cuautitlán, Tepotzotlán, Huehuetoca, and Teoloyucan.
  - 4379 Portilla, J. de la. Mexico, June 28, 1850. ALS., 2 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Request for extension of leave; illness of wife; plans to move to Morelos; Cuautla; effects of the cholera.
  - 4380 Ortega, Eulalio María. Mexico, June 28, 1850. ALS., 2 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Account of illness; Otero; spread of cholera.
  - 4381 [Anónimo.] [Carta sin firma al Lic. Agustín Díaz en Tecamac.] Coatepec, June 29, 1850., 2 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Death of José Hidalgo; Pepillo; deaths in Zoquiap[a]n.
  - 4382 Zamora, José. [Carta al Lic. Agustín Díaz en Tecamac.] June 29, 1850. ALS., 2 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Congratulations on new curato; progress of the epidemic in Chim[]n, Ayotla, Tlapacoya, Istap[]ca, Buenavista, Zoq[]n, Tlalm[]co, Chicoloap[]n, Cuautlalp[]n, Coatlich[]n, Huexotla, and Tequixquinahuac; colerina.
  - 4383 Zamora, Blas. Coatepec, June 29 (?), 1850. ALS., 2 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Record of deaths from cholera in Chimalhuacán, San Vicente, Zoquiapan, Acuautla, Coatepec; remedies.
  - 4384 Villaseñor, Alejandro. Cuernavaca, June 30, 1850. LS., 2 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Illness of members of his family; complaint from Jonacatepec.
  - 4385 García, F[ernando]. Cuernavaca, June 30, 1850. ALS., 2 l. 21 × 27 cm.
    Illness of wife; appointment to Tulancingo; account of the inconveniences caused by the proposed move to Tulancingo.